Mss.530.1.Ar2
American Philosophical Society
- I. Papers
  - Manuscript, "Ableitung der Impuls-Energie Gleichungen," [Derivative of the pulse-energy equations], 1927; 4.0 p.; Lorentz, H. A., (Hendrik Antoon), 1853-1928 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 9)
    Deutsches Museum, Munich, Germany. Letters to Leo Graetz, 1901; to Max von Laue, 1913; to Woldemar Voigt, 47 letters, 1883-1919; to Wilhelm Wien, 24 letters, 1898-1915. Algemeen Rijksarchief, The Hague, Netherlands. Papers left by Lorentz covering the period 1888-1928, containing letters from Louis de Broglie, Paul Ehrenfest, Albert Einstein, Arthur Erich Haas, Heike Kamerlingh Onnes, W. H. Keesom, Hendrik Anthony Kramers, Albert A. Michelson, Robert Andrews Millikan, L. S. Ornstein, Ernest Rutherford, Pieter Zeeman. A brief inventory has been published in Inventarissen van rijks- en andere archieven 2 (The Hague, 1930).
    Bibliotheek der Rijksuniversiteit, Leiden, Netherlands. 24 letters by Lorentz, 1876-1927.
    Rijksmuseum voor de Geschiedenis der Natuurwetenschappen, Leiden, Netherlands. Extensive correspondence with Paul Ehrenfest, for the most part personal, 1915-1928. Includes remarks by Lorentz on P. A. M. Dirac's "Physical interpretation of quantum dynamics."
    Pauli Collection, Zurich, Switzerland. Letter to Wolfgang Pauli, 1927.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 30 letters, 1900-1919.
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Lorenz, Richard, 1863-1929 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 1923; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (7 pages); Lorenz, Richard, 1863-1929 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 18)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1901; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Love, A. E. H., (Augustus Edward Hough), 1863-1940 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Lowry, T. Martin, (Thomas Martin), 1874-1936 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941-1945; 10.0 Item(s) 10 letters (20 pages); Lubonski, J. T. (Reel 12, Reel-frame 17)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Lüdi, Fritz, 1903-1963 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 25 October 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Lyman, Theodore, 1874-1954 (Reel BSC 4, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Jens Rud Nielsen, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Lyman, Theodore, 1874-1954 (Reel BSC 6, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Ernest Rutherford, 24 January 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Lyman, Theodore, 1874-1954 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 10)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 3 letters, 1923.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. 7 letters to Heinrich Kayser, 1909-1914. (Darmstaedter Collection, Flc 1910).
    Harvard University Archives, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Folder of information.
  - Letter to Pascual Jordan, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Maar, M. (Reel 18, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Maar, M. (Reel 8, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1944; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Maass, Hans (Reel 32, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1902; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (6 pages); Macdonald, Hector Munro, 1865-1935 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 22 January 1930 - 21 September 1932; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (10 pages); Mack, Julian Ellis, 1903-1966 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 1, Reel 64, Reel-frame 1-2, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); MacKaye, James, 1872-1935 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1919; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); MacLeod, Andries Hugo Donald (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Walther Gerlach, 6 March 1921 - 17 June 1922; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Madelung, Erwin, 1881-1972 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 11 November 1919 - 25 April 1925; 8.0 Item(s) 8 letters (11 pages); Madelung, Erwin, 1881-1972 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 9 October 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Madelung, Erwin, 1881-1972 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letters to Walther Gerlach, 1921-1922; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (7 pages); Magnus, A. (Reel 19, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 1922; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Magnus, A. (Reel 4, Reel-frame 18)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Magnus, Wilhelm, 1907-1990 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1900; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Maier, Max (Reel 32, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1916-1920; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Makower, W., (Walter), b. 1879 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1898; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Mangoldt, Hans von, 1854-1925 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 16 December 1931 - 5 January 1932; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Manneback, Charles, b. 1894 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 5-6)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 8 September 1926 - November 1933; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters; Manneback, Charles, b. 1894 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 10, Reel 43, Reel-frame 4)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 11 letters, 1931-1946.
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1946-1947; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (7 pages); March, Arthur, 1891-1957 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1913; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Marcolongo, Roberto, 1862-1943 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Marconi, Guglielmo, marchese, 1874-1937 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1934-1935; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (23 pages); Margenau, Henry, 1901-1997 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Marie, C. (Reel 65, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1947; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (6 pages); Mark, H. F., (Herman Francis), 1895-1992 (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1, Reel 10, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1925-1926; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (7 pages); Mark, J. van der (Reel 60, Reel-frame 8, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1914; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Marke, Axel Waldbuhm, b. 1883 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 12 June 1913; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Marsden, Ernest, Sir, 1889-1970 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 1)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 10 letters, 1946-1962.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. Letters to Ernest Rutherford, 1914-1930.
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, Circa 1932-1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Marshall, Roy Kenneth, b. 1907 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Martinette, Renato (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Marton, L., (Ladislaus), 1901-1979 (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1950; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Maue, August Wilhelm, 1908-1970 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Pascual Jordan, Late 1920s; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Mayer, Maria Goeppert, 1906-1972 (Reel 18, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1928-1929; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (3 pages); McClenahan, Howard, 1872-1935 (Reel 63, Reel-frame 1, Reel 62, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1930-1935; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (5 pages); McGraw-Hill Book Company. (Reel 52, Reel-frame 1, Reel 54, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 15 February 1913 - 19 July 1913; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); McLaren, Samuel Bruce, 1876-1916 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, September 1920 - 28 November 1922; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (6 pages); McLennan, J. C., (John Cunningham), 1867-1935 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 7 November 1929 - 9 December 1929; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (3 pages); McLennan, J. C., (John Cunningham), 1867-1935 (Reel 63, Reel-frame 7)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 14 letters, 1923-1924.
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Mecke, E. (Reel 4, Reel-frame 18)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1925; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Mecke, Reinhard, 1895-1969 (Reel 52, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Mecklin, John Moffatt, 1871-1956 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 18 August 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Meggers, William F., (William Frederick), 1888-1966 (Reel 61, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Allen Goodrich Shenstone, 9 August 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Meggers, William F., (William Frederick), 1888-1966 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1936-1941; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (6 pages); Meggers, William F., (William Frederick), 1888-1966 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 6)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 3 letters, 1925-1928.
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1901-1904; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Mehmke, Rudolf, 1857-1944 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 1925; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Meissner, Karl Wilhelm, 1891-1959 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 18)
    Microfilm index has author listed as Walther Meissner.
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 14 November 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Meitner, Lise, 1878-1968 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 12 February 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Meitner, Lise, 1878-1968 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1952; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (10 pages); Meitner, Lise, 1878-1968 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 4 letters, 1940-1946.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. 2 letters to Ernest Rutherford, 1926-1929.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letter to C. W. Oseen, 1941.
    Pauli Collection, Zurich, Switzerland. 2 letters to Wolfgang Pauli, 1956-1958.
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1946-1950; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Meixner, Josef, 1908-1994 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Mendelssohn, K., (Kurt), 1906-1980 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Mendenhall, Charles E., (Charles Elwood), 1872-1935 (Reel 52, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1923-1934; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (3 pages); Mendenhall, Charles E., (Charles Elwood), 1872-1935 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Meng, Heinrich, 1887-1972 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1926-1927; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (7 pages); Mensing, Lucie (Reel 61, Reel-frame 5, Reel 60, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Adalbert Rubinowicz, 1929-1930; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (4 pages); Merrill, Paul W., (Paul Willard), 1887-1961 (Reel 17, Reel-frame B)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1945; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); J. M. Meulenhoff, Uitgever. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1923-1928; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Meyer, Charles F., (Charles Ferdinand), b. 1887 (Reel 52, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 26 January 1920 - 29 August 1920; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Meyer, Edgar, 1879-1960 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Walther Gerlach, 16 March 1922 - 30 August 1929; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (9 pages); Meyer, Edgar, 1879-1960 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 29 September 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Meyer, Edgar, 1879-1960 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 12 February 1912 - 9 April 1913; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (7 pages); Meyer, Edgar, 1879-1960 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 6)
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 2 letters, 1918.
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1912-1921; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (11 pages); Meyer, Kirstine Bjerrum, 1861-1941 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Meyer, L. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Meyer, Martin (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Meyer, P. H. E. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1930; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Meyer, Stefan, 1872-1949 (Reel 64, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Meyer, Stefan, 1872-1949 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1938; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Michalski, Stanislaw, 1865-1949 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Michels, Antonius, 1889-1969 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 13 October 1925 - 14 December 1925; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (6 pages); Mie, Gustav, 1868-1957 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 18)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 14 July 1900 - 1 February 1935; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (19 pages); Mie, Gustav, 1868-1957 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 7)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 2 letters, 1924-1928.
    Sächsische Landesbibliothek, Dresden, Germany. Letter from the Nachlass of and perhaps addressed to Oberkirchenrat D. Neuberg, 1936.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. Letter to Ludwig Darmstaedter, 1910; to Leo Grunmach, 1906; to Meigen, 1925. (Darmstaedter Collection, Fle 1900).
    Deutsches Museum, Munich, Germany. Letter to Max von Laue, 1912; letter to Carl Runge, 1906.
    Bibliothek der Eidgenössischen Technischen Hochschule, Zurich, Switzerland. Letters to Hermann Weyl, 2 letters, 1918-1930.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 8 letters, 1918-1926.
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1916; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages) (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Miescher, E. F. (Reel 54, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933-1936; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (11 pages); Miller, Dayton Clarence, 1866-1941 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to J. H. Van Vleck, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Miller, Dayton Clarence, 1866-1941 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 15 December 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868-1953 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 12 March 1930; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868-1953 (Reel 64, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 22 October 1927 - 25 November 1927; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868-1953 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 7)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 16 letters, 1924-1947.
    California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California. An extensive collection of Millikan's papers including a draft version of his autobiography.
    Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. Correspondence with Oswald Veblen, 1922-1926.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 8 letters, 1923-1933.
    American Institute of Physics, New York, New York. Letters to Gordon Fulcher, 3 letters, 1921-1923.
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1945; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Minderaa, P. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1899-1908; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (7 pages); Minkowski, H., (Hermann), 1864-1909 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 19 July 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Minkowski, Rudolf, 1895-1976 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 2)
  - Postcard to Fräulein Hedwig Kohn, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 postcard (1 page); Minkowski, Rudolf, 1895-1976 (Reel 3, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 15 November 1945; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Minkowski, Rudolf, 1895-1976 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Minnaert, M. G. J., (Marcel Gilles Jozef), 1893-1970 (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1919; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Minnaert, M. G. J., (Marcel Gilles Jozef), 1893-1970 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1903; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Mohr, Otto (Reel 32, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (12 pages); Molendijk, L. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hans A. Bethe, 30 September 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Møller, C., (Christian), 1904-1981 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to F. C. Champion, 1931-1932; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (4 pages); Møller, C., (Christian), 1904-1981 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Max Delbrück, 14 October 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Møller, C., (Christian), 1904-1981 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Werner Heisenberg, 4 December 1931 - 15 December 1931; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Møller, C., (Christian), 1904-1981 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to N. F. Mott, 9 December 1931 - 25 January 1932; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Møller, C., (Christian), 1904-1981 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 18 letters, 1928-1957. Letter to André Mercier, 1946.
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Morse, Philip M., (Philip McCord), 1903-1985 (Reel 63, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1900; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (8 pages); Morton, William Blair, 1868-1949 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 16 November 1913; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (6 pages); Moseley, H. G. J., (Henry Gwyn Jeffreys), 1887-1915 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Charles Galton Darwin, 17 January 1914 - 1 February 1914; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (16 pages); Moseley, H. G. J., (Henry Gwyn Jeffreys), 1887-1915 (Reel 36, Reel-frame 1)
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. 3 letters to Georg von Hevesy; letters to Ernest Rutherford, 191?-1915. Photographs. Correspondence about printing of photograph for distribution, 1925. Rutherford's obituary notice of Moseley. Article by Rutherford, "Moseley's work on X-rays." Notes by Moseley made on board ship.
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Moss, S. (Reel 52, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1944; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Mostert, C. A. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to William Lawrence Bragg, 1950; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Mott, N. F., Sir, (Nevill Francis), 1905-1996 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1939; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (8 pages); Mott, N. F., Sir, (Nevill Francis), 1905-1996 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Christian Møller, 15 December 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Mott, N. F., Sir, (Nevill Francis), 1905-1996 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 18 May 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Mott, N. F., Sir, (Nevill Francis), 1905-1996 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 8)
  - Memoir, "Notes by Professor Mott on his Personal Experiences of the Development of Quantum Physics", 18 March 1962; 3.0 p.; Mott, N. F., Sir, (Nevill Francis), 1905-1996 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 12)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 25 letters, 1929-1958.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letters to Fritz London, 15 letters, 1930-1936.
  - Letter to Linus Pauling, 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Mott-Smith, Morton Churchill, 1877-1944 (Reel 74, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Muck, Otto Heinrich (Reel 32, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947-1948; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Mulders, Gerardus Franciscus Wilhelmus (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 19 December 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Mulliken, Robert Sanderson, 1896-1986 (Reel 63, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 21 July 1926 - 23 October 1935; 14.0 Item(s) 14 letters (59 pages); Mulliken, Robert Sanderson, 1896-1986 (Reel 52, Reel-frame 2, Reel 54, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 10 March 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Mulliken, Robert Sanderson, 1896-1986 (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to J. H. Van Vleck, 8 February 1927 - 1 July 1935; 17.0 Item(s) 17 letters (53 pages); Mulliken, Robert Sanderson, 1896-1986 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 11)
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letters to Fritz London, 1951.
    University of Chicago Library, Chicago, Illinois. Robert S. Mulliken Papers, 63 linear feet, 1908-1985.
  - Register Volume, December 1908 - May 1939; 189.0 p.; Münchener Physikalisches Mittwochs-Colloquium. (Reel 20)
    Includes record of the dates, speakers, and titles of the talks given to the Munich Colloquium, 1908 to 1939.
    Original held at the Institute for Theoretical Physics, University of Munich.
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (5 pages); Murdock, Kenneth B. (Reel 54, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 27 December 1913 - 23 March 1921; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Nagaoka, Hantaro, 1865-1950 (Reel BSC 5, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 24 January 1930; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Nagaoka, Hantaro, 1865-1950 (Reel 64, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 16 March 1922 - 4 January 1924; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Nagaoka, Hantaro, 1865-1950 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 19)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 2 letters, 1931.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. Letters to Ernest Rutherford, 2 letters, 1911-1919.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. Letter to the Secrétaire de la Société de Physique et d'Histoire Naturelle, Geneva, undated. (Darmstaedter Collection, La* 1896).
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1950; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Nanta, W. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 1925; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Natanson, Wladyslaw, 1864-1937 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 19)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); National Cyclopedia of American Biography. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Hendirk Anthony Kramers, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); National Fonds voor Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek. (Reel 12, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1924-1925; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); National Research Council (U.S.) (Reel 52, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Nature. (Reel 8, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (17 pages); Naturforscher-Versammlung. Salzburg. (Reel 8, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Natuurkundig Gezelschap. Middelburg. (Reel 10, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946-1947; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Nederlands Genootschap voor Internationale Zaken. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1, Reel 12, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Nederlandse Natuurkundige Vereniging. (Reel 13, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 7 August 1934 - 31 March 1935; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (6 pages); Nernst, Walther, 1864-1941 (Reel 32, Reel-frame 9)